Finding Aid for John Cornelius Christensen papers, 1912-1948
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John Cornelius Christensen papers 1912-1948
Christensen, John Cornelius, 1874-1952.
4 linear feet
85949 Aa 2
Assistant secretary, 1914-1931, and controller, 1931-1944, of the University of Michigan. Correspondence, financial reports and studies, speeches, articles, and other papers relating to the business office of the University, the American Council on Education, and the General Education Board; also financial studies on various colleges and educational institutes.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were transferred from the Business Office of the University of Michigan (donor no. 1801 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
John Cornelius Christensen was born August 18, 1874 in Riley County, Kansas. He received his B.S. in 1894 from Kansas State Agricultural College. He taught school for a time then enrolled at the University of Kansas. He left to become a bookkeeper, bank cashier, and financial secretary. He came to the University of Michigan in 1914 as assistant secretary and purchasing agent. In 1931, he became controller and assistant secretary, a position he held until his retirement in 1944. He died September 30, 1951.
The collection includes correspondence, speeches, and other materials relating to his career in Kansas and at the University of Michigan. Some of the files relate to his activities with the Association of Business Officers of the State Universities and College of the Middle West. There are a few photographic portraits.
Subjects:
American Council on Education.; Christensen, John Cornelius, 1874-1952.; Education--United States.; General Education Board.; University of Michigan--Administration.; University of Michigan. Business Office.; University of Michigan. Controller.; University of Michigan--Finance.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Christensen, John Cornelius, 1874-1952.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  - 1912-1913 (Box 1)
  - 1920-1928, 34 folders (Box 1)
  - 1929-1937, 35 folders (Box 2)
  - 1938-1948, 23 folders (Box 3)
- Speeches, reports and other writings
  (include materials of the Association of Business Officers of the State Universities and College of the Middle West)
  - Undated and 1912-1921, 8 folders (Box 3)
  - 1922-1945, 7 folders (Box 4)
- Other papers
  - Reports on college business organization and accounting practices prepared by John Christensen for the Carnegie Corporation (Box 4)
  - Papers re Phi Kappa Phi activities, 1928-1941, 2 folders (Box 4)
  - Photographs: portraits, individual and group (Box 4)